Let's talk about the solution for lesson one exercise two,
creating a table with Apache Cassandra.
In this exercise, we walked through the basics of creating
a table in Apache Cassandra and inserting rows of data.
We then did a simple CQL query to
validate actually to say CQL query to validate the information.
So, anywhere that you saw the pound sign,
you'll need to fill in that code.
So of course we're going to "import" our Python driver, "import" Cassandra.
Then we're going to create that connection to the database,
and then we're going to test out our connection,
just to make sure that even though we didn't get an error thrown back,
let's just double-check that we're able to connect to the database.
Great. No keyspace. We got an error,
which is what we were expecting.
No keyspace has been defined.
Use the keyspace or explicitly say a keyspace.table name.
Okay, makes sense. So let's create our keyspace so that we can do our work from it.
Ignore the replication strategy and factor information for now.
These will be discussed later.
Just know that well one node local instance,
this will be your strategy and replication factor.
So we're going to create a keyspace if it does not exist.
And then we're going to connect to our keyspace.
All right, let's get to data modeling.
Let's imagine we'd like to start creating a song library of all the songs we own.
Each song has a lot of information we could add to the song library table,
but we'll just start with the name of the song, artist's name, year,
album it was from,
and if it was a single,
if it wasn't part of an album.
So, song title, artist,
year, album and then single.
But stop. We're working with Apache Cassandra, a NoSQL database.
We can't model our data and create our table without more information.
What queries will I be performing on this data?
If you remember to ask this question whenever you're
doing data modeling in Apache Cassandra, you're in a good spot.
In this case, I'd like to be able to get every song by
certain artists that was released in a particular year.
Select 'start' from songs where year equals 1970,
and artist name equals The Beatles.
Because of this, I need to be able to do aware on year.
Year will become our partition key,
and artist name we might clustering column to make each primary key unique.
Remember, there are no duplicates in Apache Cassandra.
Now translate this to a create table statement.
Don't worry if any of this seems confusing.
All of lesson three we'll focus heavily on these topics.
Create table if it does not exist called songs.
We're going to have a year of an Int.
Song title is text,
artist's name is text,
album name text and then we're going to have
whether it was a single or not and we're going to represent that with a Boolean.
From there we're going to do our primary key as year and artist's name.
Let's create that table.
Great. No error was found.
But let's check to ensure our table was created.
Let's do a quick select count star,
which should return zero as we have not answered any rows.
Depending on your version of Apache Cassandra you haven't solved,
this might throw and allow filtering error instead of the result of zero.
This is to be expected as this type of query should not be performed on large data sets.
We're only doing this for the sake of the demo.
Again, much more on this in lesson three.
Select count star from songs.
So in my case actually I've already created this table and
inserted rows and that's why you're not seeing zero and you're seeing two.
Let's insert two rows across the universe.
The Beatles 1970 falls and let it be.
And the second row, The Beatles Think for yourself falls
1965 and Rubber Soul. So we're going to insert those.
Again, note the query here.
Note the insert statement with the values and then we're inserting the values.
Wonderful. Validate your data was inserted into the table.
The for loop is used for printing the results.
If executing this query in CQLSH,
which is a shell program that you can use to run a CQL queries,this will not be required.
Depending on the version of Apache Cassandra you have installed,
this again might throw and allow
filtering error instead of putting the two rows we just inserted.
This is to be expected as this type of query should not be performed on large data sets.
We're only doing this for the sake of the demo.
Again much more on this in lesson three.
Awesome, we got back our two rows.
Let's validate our data model with our original query.
Select star from songs where year equals 1970 and artist name equals The Beatles.
Wonderful, we got back our row.
Great. Success. Finally, let's close out our session and our cluster connection.
And we're done with the exercise.